

# Oda Schneider

# Front-End Developer (M.sc. Pharma-Biotechnology)

## **About Me**

# Oda Schneider Altranstädter Straße 19 04229, Leipzig

0049/17655694254 contact@oda-schneider.com

Portfolio: www.oda-schneider.com

I am a Web Developer with experience in building web apps with JavaScript & Angular. You can find my projects that include responsive websites and business apps in my public porftolio. My journey began as a technical assistant until I decided to evolve and study biotechnology. After I finished my master's degree, I became a mother and that brought many changes in my life, such as the desire to reorient myself professionally. I had my first experiences with programming during my bachelor studies with Python. Since I liked the structural and solution-oriented thinking process, I decided to deepen my skills in programming and started at a professional software development school (Developer Akademie in Munich). Now I am looking forward to building on my experience and starting my career in IT in a junior developer position.

#### Main Stack:

- JavaScript
- TypeScript, Angular, Material Design
- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

#### Side Stack:

- Git, APIs (REST), Google Firebase, Scrum

#### **Skills**

- Building Applications with JavaScript & Angular: I built landing-pages and several web apps as well as OOP-based Jump-and-Run-Games with the respective technologies.
- Working in a Software-Team: During learning coding, I did several group projects where I learned how to develop a software project in a team
- **High sense of responsibility:** Working in the lab taught me to work diligently, stay organized, and keep track of complex processes, which helped me learn programming quickly.
- Ability to work problem-oriented: In science, I learned to analyze problems and focus on important steps to find quick solutions.

## **Professional Experience**

#### **University Hospital / MasterStudent**

Apr 2018 - Sep 2019 PRESENT, Jena

- Establishment of primary cell culture
- Development of standard operating procedures for analysis
- Analysis of age-associated expression profile

#### 4-Antibody Ag/ Bachelor Student

Mar 2016 - Jul 2016, Jena

- Establishment of methods for specific labeling of antigens in tumor therapy
- Self-reliant research and analysis of the results
- Test optimization

#### Ernst-Abbe-Hochschule / Student Research Project

Aug 2015 - Sep 2015, Jena

- Self-organized student research project about reactive oxygen species
- 3rd place at university poster competition

#### **Education**

# **Developer Akademie** / JavaScript & Angular Web Development Training

Apr 2022 - Nov 2022, Munich

Project based coding academy. Main Stack: JavaScript, Angular

Portfolio: www.oda-schneider.com

Extensive Coding School, Learning Front-End Development, Coding, Agile Project Management and building several projects in teams and alone.

# Ernst-Abbe-Hochschule / M.Sc. Pharma-Biotechnology

Oct 2016 - Sep 2019, Jena

Biotechnology based drug development.

Enzyme Technology, Low Molecular Pharmaceuticals, Molecular Medicine, Recombinant Products, Genetic / Protein Engineering.

#### Ernst-Abbe-Hochschule / B.Eng. Biotechnology

Sep 2013 - Sep 2016, Jena

Use of biomolecules, cells and whole organisms in technical applications.

Informatics (Phyton), Biotechnological Facilities, Laboratory Analysis, Biosensors, Biomaterials, Technical Microbiology.

## Languages

German: native

English: good knowledge Spanish: good knowledge